Part of the backup process is the occasional
need to restore data. Sometimes, data is
deleted accidentally. Sometimes, data can become
corrupt. And, as part of the backup process,
a data restore should be tested on occasion to
make sure the restore works when it is needed.
I have backed up the AdventureWorks2019 database
and I want to restore it to this SQL instance,
as someone accidentally deleted a table in the
database. Do keep in mind that restores overwrite
existing data, which is why it is important
to back up data frequently. I will select
and hold (or right-click) AdventureWorks2019,
and then select Tasks, Restore, and Database.
Available restores will show here in the Backup
sets to restore area. Any backup can be verified
through selecting it and then Verify Backup
Media. Though this step is not necessary,
I do want to make sure this backup is ready to
restore, so I will select Verify Backup Media.
I don't see any error messages, so I will
select the Ok button to restore this database,
and we get a message indicating a successful
restoration of the data has taken place.
Remember, a backup is only as good as
one's ability to restore said backup.